This tutorial demonstrates adjusting my
spin settings for my ideal creamy
texture. Following various scrape tests,
let's begin. By scraping a spoon on out
my frozen mixture, I get a feel for what
setting to use. This mix is hard and
I'll use the sorbet setting. I spun it
with no thawing and right out of the
freezer. This one is really soft. I'll
use ice cream setting then mix in. It
will likely result in soft serve. I can
skip mix in or freeze for a bit after.
It is important to note this is based on
my machine freezer and mixes. You may
need to experiment. In my opinion, when
learning, the safest first spin is
sorbet. I can tell this will be perfect.
Sorbet and mix in will be my ideal
texture.
For softer serve, I would mix in twice.
Alternatively, if not adding mix ins,
one respin after sorbet would likely be
ideal. For even softer, three spins max.
Sorbet respin mix in. This is a very
flexible result.
This is another one that is questionably
soft. I'd probably freeze it longer or
use ice cream plus mix in, accepting it
may be more like soft serve. Absolutely
no thawing and not a higher setting. It
would turn to soup. If not adding mix
ins, sometimes one spin is enough on the
right setting.
This one after one spin was half
pebbles, half powder. Push down method
assist in doing only one spin to
perfection. Two spins total. Without
push down method, this may have needed
an extra two plus spins. No liquid was
needed. The push down also allowed the
sides to get incorporated into the rest
of the creamy. Even before spinning, the
push down gave an almost ice cream like
result. Depending on preference, this
could be enough. I still need to add my
mix in so I will spin it again two spins
total. It will still be my ideal hard
ice cream result. Had I not used the
push down, I may have mistakenly over
spun it and got a soft serve result. If
that is your preference, no biggie. This
is another creamy following these
methods. This was after the second spin,
mix in. Before the second spin, there
were hard icy sides. The push down
method allowed those to be processed.
Thanks for watching!